#### CURRICULUM VITÆ

# **Hugh Lilly**

Auckland, New Zealand

**≢** hughlilly@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/hughlilly

I have 12 years' experience in the Galleries, Libraries, Archives, and Museums sector in Aotearoa New Zealand. I have extensive knowledge of a wide variety of software platforms, programming languages, front-end frameworks, UI libraries, and modern build tools, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, C#, Python, Office 365, the Adobe Creative Suite, and Figma.

I have an excellent command of written and spoken English, and elementary te reo Māori. I am well-versed in tikanga Māori. I can work to self-appointed deadlines, within an Agile environment. I have excellent organisational, problem-solving, and time-management skills, and can easily prioritise competing demands.

I have proven research expertise, and devote myself to reaching solutions that satisfy all stakeholders. I show initiative by resolving issues and challenges independently, asking for support and advice only when necessary, and respond proactively to feedback.

# **Employment History**

#### Auckland War Memorial Museum Tāmaki Paenga Hira

January-February 2022

July 2016-December 2021

November 2012-July 2016

#### The New Zealand Listener

June 2012-January 2013

# **Systems Librarian**

Developed, implemented, and supported robust information-systems applications that enhanced the discoverability of library-related services and collections to colleagues, academic researchers, and the wider public.

#### **Research Support Co-ordinator**

- Streamlined onsite and online research systems to deliver an integrated, efficient and researcher-centric service. Held primary responsibility for the administration of the museum's enquiry-management system.
- Worked extensively on the UX design of the museum's flagship digital products, Collections Online and Online Cenotaph. Integrated Digital Object Identifiers and Open Researcher and Contributor IDs into the museum's existing Content Management System.
- Planned, wrote, and copyedited dozens of Topic Pages (blog posts) on the museum website which focus on the acquisition, display, and conservation histories of collection objects, and the stories they tell.

#### **Assistant Librarian, Acquisitions**

Managed the acquisitions (purchase and donation) process for monographic publications, including database management and creating invoicing processes and policies. Assisted with the preservation, care, and rehousing of documentary-heritage taonga in the publications, pictorial, manuscripts and archives, ephemera, and map collections.

#### Freelance Film Critic

Wrote a column and 'sidebar' content for the print edition fortnightly, plus web-only content every week. Wrote in-depth reviews of 28 International Film Festival titles over the 17 days of its Auckland run.

# Education

# The University of Auckland

2006–2010

# Bachelor of Arts (Hons.)

- Undergraduate: double major in English, and in Film, Television, and Media Studies
- Postgraduate: Second-Class Honours (First Division) in Film, Television, and Media Studies (New Media and Technology)

# Whitecliffe College

2022

#### Web Development + Design

NZ Diploma in Web Development and Design (Level 5)

- HTML; CSS; JavaScript; React; Python; C#; MS-SQL
- Git; GitHub workflows; VS Code; Node.js, npm, and yarn
- Software Development Lifecycle (i.e., Agile methodology)
- UX & UI design best practices, incl. accessibility testing
- Figma for wireframing and prototyping
- Test-driven development, incl. cross-browser and UAT
- Legal and ethical concerns surrounding development

#### Te Ataarangi

2019

# Ngā Pūtake: Te Reo Māori

Te Reo Māori me ōna Tikanga

- Completed Te Ataarangi Kōwae Ako 1 Whanaungatanga
- Exam score of 98%

#### Te Wānanga o Aotearoa

2020–2021

#### He Papa Tikanga

NZ Certificate in Tikanga (Mātauranga Māori) (Level 3)

- · Māori traditions, values and belief systems
- Māori in a contemporary world
- Māori philosophies and protocols

# Merge NZ

2018

# **New Zealand Sign Language workshop**

Day-long workshop on NZSL and Deaf culture